In this course,
Istruttore: In
you learned a lot about TypeScript,
questo corso avete imparato molto
and there is one particular use case,
su TypeScript e c'è un caso d'uso particolare,
one scenario where you could also TypeScript
uno scenario in cui potreste usare TypeScript
which we hadn't had a look at thus far.
che non abbiamo ancora visto.
We've primarily focused on using TypeScript
Ci siamo concentrati principalmente sull'uso di TypeScript
to write browser site JavaScript code in the end.
per scrivere codice JavaScript per il sito del browser.
And that is totally fine
E questo va benissimo e potrebbe
and might be the most common use case
essere il caso d'uso più comune di lavorare
of working with TypeScript,
con TypeScript, ma non è l'unico.
You can also use TypeScript
È anche possibile utilizzare TypeScript
to build Node.js applications,
per costruire Node. js, ovviamente anche in
also of course in conjunction with the popular
combinazione con il popolare Express.
Now whilst Node.js on its own is not capable
js.
of executing TypeScript,
TypeScript, in questo modulo
in this module,
imparerete a utilizzare
you will learn how you can still use TypeScript
TypeScript per scrivere Node.
and we will build a very simple web application,
js
a very simple REST API here
una semplicissima API REST in cui utilizzeremo
where we also utilize TypeScript
anche TypeScript sul lato server
on the server-side with Node.js and Express.
con Node. js ed Express.
Just as in the React section,
Proprio come nella sezione React,
here's a little disclaimer for this section.
ecco un piccolo disclaimer per questa sezione.
This section here requires Node
Questa sezione richiede la conoscenza
and Express knowledge.
di Node ed Express.
It's about using TypeScript with Node, Express,
Si tratta di utilizzare TypeScript con Node, Express,
it's not teaching Node from the ground up.
ma non di insegnare Node dalle fondamenta.
So if you've never heard about Node
Quindi, se non avete mai sentito parlare
and Express before,
di Node ed Express prima d'ora,
definitely take some dedicated resources
prendete sicuramente qualche risorsa dedicata
like my Node.js The Complete Guide course first
come il mio Node. Prima di esplorare questa sezione, è necessario
before you explore this section.
seguire il corso The Complete Guide (Guida completa).
So let's dive in.
Quindi tuffiamoci.